

Muhammad Moiz Siddique

(+92) 03062890575 | muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com |

https://www.muhammadmoizsiddique.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddigue-74419b166/

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099 | Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991

Al-minal tower, Block 3A, Gulistan e Johar, Karachi, Sindh, 75200, Karachi, Pakistan About me:

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Associate Software Developer with over 3+ years of experience leading projects by acting as an architect, developer and programmer analyst.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/06/2019 - 30/05/2022 - Karachi, Pakistan

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ALGORACK

My journey with Algorack as associate software engineer was a great experiences for me. I deal with clients, developed modules for frontend, backend and mobile apps, API integration, write code with modern approaches or industrial best practices. The responsibilities further include code refactoring, testing(unit, integration and e2e). I have further improved my verbal and written communication skills as I dealt with international clients along the way, mentoring and guiding junior.

01/09/2018 – 31/10/2018 – Krachi, Pakistan INTERNSHIP – KARACHI PORT TRUST (KPT)

It was a great experience while working in one of the biggest organizations in Pakistan. I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals, through whom I learnt (Dot) Net programming language. I was exposed to the software infrastructure used in such a large sized professional company. This opportunity also allowed me to thoroughly understand how data center are utilized in such large organizations works. This further helped me increase my team-working creditability working within a professional IT department and understanding the workplace dynamic.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/10/2017 – 18/07/2021 – Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, Karachi, Pakistan **BACHLOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE –** Muhammad Ali Jinnah University

01/08/2015 - 30/04/2017 - Karachi, Pakistan

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL EDUCATION (HSC) - Govt. Islamia Science College

01/03/2013 - 30/04/2015 - Saddar, Karachi, Pakistan

SECONDARY SCHOOL EDUCATION (SSC) - Hyderi Public School

PROJECTS

2019

WORKING ON WEB APP SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO

https://www.socialchamp.io/

I'm responsible for design and develop new modules in Angular, maintain and manage existing application including bug fixes, analyze requirement and estimate ETAs and client meetings.

https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/

I design, develop and manage data pipelines and cloud architectures (google) with efficient processing and management of large amounts of data, collection and management of data in ML, develop interfaces / APIs for data exchange in python and manage frontend using Angular

2021

WORKING ON WEB APP DXP FE-Component

https://www.dxpe.com/

I develop well-designed, testable, efficient code and troubleshoot, debug and upgrade existing systems. Release test automation through CI/CD, code analysis.(React js, Node js, jenkins, docker, Azure).

2022

Bright Development

https://bright-development.com/

I manage multi-cloud environment system using AWS & GCP, created large scaleable micro-services (Node js), daily updates CI/CD and docker, deployments on AWS, manage COSMOS DB & SQL and design & develop frontend modules (React js).

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Programming, Web and App Development | Business Analysis | Design and Data Visualization | Project Management | Product Management | Quick problem solving | Teamwork oriented | Strategic planning

Professional Skills

Language Skills

Urdu (Native) | English (Fluent) | Turkish (Basics)

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/06/2022

JavaScript: Core And Advanced Techniques - Udemy: Online Courses

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-0c1bcfe1-3e17-4c6d-944a-e2151435ab66/

06/2020

Code Jam - Google

https://codingcompetitions.withgoogle.com/codejam/certificate/summary/00000000001857b3

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Interests

Speed Programming competitions / Learning new courses and certifications / Travelling / Poetry / Guitar/Music / Football / Puzzles and games / Streaming